# Narayana Harricharan

narayan-das@tuta.io Download PDF



Name: Narayana Harricharan

Date of birth: 25/08/1993

Nationality: South African

Languages: English and Afrikaans

**Profile** 

I am a highly unique individual, I have been embracing a wide variety of cultures ever since I can remember and can therefore easily relate to different kinds of people. I like to consider myself a well balanced person and I have a deep thirst for knowledge both technical and metaphysical.

I specialize in DevOps Engineering, but can work on all aspects of the stack from frontend to backend. A role that would excite me would be a mixture of DevOps and backend coding.

#### DevOps experience:

- Designing, building, monitoring, debugging and maintaining high traffic linux servers and systems
- Building CI/CD systems
- Site migrations

- Dockerizing web application and other services
- Infra as Code

#### Backend coding experience:

- Writing API's in Typescript
- Writing unit tests in Typescript
- Scripting in Bash, NodeJS and Ruby

# Experience

#### Freelancer

DevOps Engineer SEPTEMBER 2019 - DECEMBER 2019

- Migrating a LAMP Stack website from bare metal server to AWS
- SensorNetworks Assisting them in creating helm charts and a monitoring solution

## OneConfig

DevOps Engineer APRIL 2019 - AUGUST 2019

Duties: Daily housekeeping and DevOps/Sysadmin tasks. I was in charge of 30+ servers. My tasks included: updating Letsencrypt certs, migrating servers, creating servers, adding new servers to DB clusters, troubleshooting any server related issues, optimizing costs, patching servers, automation in Ansible, Bash and Go. The biggest project I worked on was dockerizing the staging environment with the goal to be able to host multiple staging environments on one server.

• Technologies used: Linux | Nginx | Bash | Docker | KVM | Ansible | Digital Ocean | Check MK | Scylla DB Cluster | Cockroach DB Cluster | LetsEncrypt | Tiny bit of HA Proxy and Go

## **Kurtosys**

Platform Engineer AUGUST 2017 - MARCH 2019

This was a hybrid role where I was both involved with ops engineerings and full stack development. My role is to help develop and architect a full stack application that requires automation of DNS, TLS, Git functionality, MySQL administration, Docker, Docker Swarm, Kong and Wordpress in following languages: Nodejs, Typescript, React and Bash. We use Glusterfs for a distributed file system. Configuration manangement tools used: Ansible and Puppet. My duties also consist of supporting a security optimized Wordpress hosting platform and an internal Gitlab server.

Technologies used: AWS - Lambda, Fargate | CDN - CloudFlare | Virtualization - Docker Swarm, Vagrant | Coding - NodeJS,
TypeScript, React | Infra as Code - Ansible, Puppet | Tech - GlusterFS, Kong, Gitlab

#### **Manalto**

DevOps Engineer MARCH 2017 - JULY 2017

Duties: Troubleshooting all production and staging issues. Working alongside developers/QA as needed. Setting up and maintaining infrastructure, mongodb, AWS services and CI/CD. I setup Manalto's entire infrastructure which consisted out of many micro services in docker. I also setup CI/CD with Bitbucket pipelines and Jenkins for the new docker environment. I wrote all the dockerfiles from scratch in Alpine Linux. Bash scripting - Automated AWS Route53 cname creation, init.d start scripts, docker management script, etc. Adding AWS Cloudwatch graphs to Grafana. Setting up a private npm registry. Deep diving code to help troubleshoot or understand the application to dockerize.

 Technologies used: AWS - Elasticbeanstalk, Cloudfront, SQS, SNS, Lambda, Dynamodb, Cloudwatch | Docker | CI/CD - Deploybot, serveless, Bitbucket pipelines, Jenkins

#### **OLX**

DevOps Engineer APRIL 2016 - JANUARY 2017

I helped managed 6 OLX's websites in africa: olx.co.za, olx.com.ng, olx.co.ke, olx.com.gh, olx.co.ug, olx.co.tz. our biggest website olx.co.za by itself serves millions of pageviews per day. when i first joined we ran a LAMP stack on bare metal servers running Ubuntu. Our stack included Redis, Memcache and Solr. We used Akamai CDN, Cisco firewalls, and F5 Big IP load balancers. For graphing and logs: Graphite, Graphana and ELK stack. Alerting: Sensu. Jenkins was used for continuous delivery system. We rebuilt and migrated our infrastructure to run in containers on AWS in September. All our infrastructure was written in code with Terrafrom and Ansible of which i only contributed a small amount of Ansible changes after the migrations had taken place. We used Kubernetes to manage and orchestrate our containers. We switched to the following AWS services: AWS ELB, RDS, Elasticache (Memcache and Redis). Our continuous delivery system expanded to include in house software called "Argo". Argo is responsible for setting up our project needs and communicates with Kubernetes to be easily deployed through Jenkins. Our graphing, alerting and logging applications used where: Sysdig, New Relic, Papertrail.

Technology used: Graphing – Graphana, New Relic, Dashing and Kibana | Alerting - Sensu, New Relic, Sysdig | Logging - Papertrail, Elastic Search and Logstash | CI/CD - Jenkins and Argo | Automation - Terraform, Ansible and Bash | Troubleshooting – Redis, Memcache, MySQL, Big IP F5 Load balancer | AWS – EC2, ELB, VPC, Route53, RDS, IAM, S3 | Other - Git, Ruby, Docker, writing documentation, security, site's stability and adding features for developers

## 8Frag

Linux Systems Administrator

JULY 2014 - APRIL 2016

Duties and Skills: Installation of SRCDS game servers (CS:GO and TF2), GOTV proxy servers, Depth knowledge of SRCDS based games, creating/modifying game server configurations, Basic SourcePawn Scripting, Installation and configuration of plug-ins for the games severs. Managing and maintaining all Ubuntu servers and software's used. Migrating and deploying of servers. Installation and configuration of UnrealIRC, TeamSpeak. AWS Skills: S3, RDS, EC2, Policies and SES. Implementation of game server web-panel TCAdmin, installing and configuring monitoring solution Pulseway which I later replaced with LibreNMS. Game Server Rental ticket, TeamSpeak support and handling escalated issues. Game Tournament support and administration. Writing tutorials on how to do manage and use services. Installation of SSL, Bash scripting, Ansible playbooks, Installation and configuring of FTP, Apache and

backup solutions. MySQL, UFW use and management, basic DDOS mitigation and process management. Duplicating and managing all of our systems on Windows 2012 server for a short time period. Full involvement and assistance with software development. Involvement with website design as well as any other ideas, projects and decisions that effect the company. Testing and finding bugs for games and applications. Managing in house developed software created in Ruby, NodeJS and Python. I Took over the Lead IT roll after our Senior Developer left . Making calls on software and hardware requirements, solutions and improvements. Managing and training our junior Linux systems administrator.

#### **Ockhams Razor**

Junior Linux Systems Administrator

FEBRUARY 2014 - APRIL 2014

I received hands on experience with Debian Servers, RAID, BASH, AWK, SED and REGEX Scripting and also in-depth knowledge on the fundamentals of Linux LPI1. My training also consisted of: apt-get package management, setting up web servers with Apache, setting up e-mail servers with Postfix, installing web sites/panels, installing and configuring ISP config, bash scripting, mail flow trouble shooting, setting up DNS and configuring network interface cards.

#### **Maxitec - Internet Service Provider**

Internet and IT Support

JANUARY 2012 - JANUARY 2014

Duties: Responding to all calls, e-mails, walk in clients and service call outs for diagnosing and resolving hardware, software and end users problems within agreed time scales. Providing efficient customer support for all issues relating to desktops, laptops, apple macs, mobile devices, peripherals, routers, WIFI, telecommunication, hosting, e-mails, VOIP and networking technologies. Taking ownership of a call/instruction and seeing it through to closure. Escalating calls and issues where necessary to seniors. Updating support documentation.IT support for 'Maxiclub' Point of Sale System and helped out with Vodacom accounts and device support.

NodeJS & Typescript	GNU/Linux - Centos & Debian	Cloud - AWS & DigitalOcean
50%	90%	70%
Ruby	Docker Swarm	Ansible
40%	90%	90%
Bash	Docker	Puppet
80%	90%	50%
CI/CD	Kubernetes & Helm	Virtualbox, KVM, Vagrant
60%	40%	70%
Monitoring & Alerting	Networking	Database Administration
80%	50%	60%

# **Projects**

github.com/Narayana108/

#### Education

## **Redhat Certified Systems Administrator**

RED HAT SEPTEMBER 2015

### **Interests**

Coding • Crystal Lang • Ruby on Rails • GNU/Linux • Ergonomical workflow • Yoga • Meditation • Hindi & Sanskrit

Website by Narayana